[{"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e0", "question": "Who wrote the first three books of the \"Millennium\" novel series?", "answer": "Stieg Larsson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a080", "question": "What was Captain Jean Luke Picard's favorite tea in \"Star Trek: The Next Generation\"?", "answer": "Earl Grey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a863", "question": "The popular tourist destination, Amalfi, is located in which province in the Italian Campania region?", "answer": "Salerno", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b413", "question": "In what year was nylon first synthesized?", "answer": "1935", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c496877e98cb977789a1", "question": "In which Canadian province do the Appalachian Mountains end?", "answer": "Newfoundland and Labrador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339037", "question": "What is non-rhyming poetry called?", "answer": "Blank verse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a43b", "question": "What is the longest river in the US?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1b8", "question": "In 2005, Bhutan became the first country to entirely ban what?", "answer": "Tobacco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389c1", "question": "What is the name of Squire Trelawney's ship in \"Treasure Island\"?", "answer": "Hispaniola", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5f2", "question": "Since 1995 which state has led the U.S. in milk production?", "answer": "California", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e4", "question": "Which popular musician co-wrote the song \"I'm afraid of Americans\" with David Bowie?", "answer": "Brian Eno", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6008dd97f4f3bc4a292f8622", "question": "\"Operation Overlord\" was the code name for the invasion of what country during World War II?", "answer": "German-occupied France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba497874c93a3298b2146", "question": "What is believed to have eventually killed Oliver Cromwell?", "answer": "Malaria and urinary/kidney infection", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389dd", "question": "What English writer died on the on the same date as Spanish author and poet Miguel de Cervantes?", "answer": "William Shakespeare", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1f3", "question": "Whose remains were thrown into the Seine River on May 30, 1431?", "answer": "Joan of Arc's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c1b", "question": "The comic books and movie titled \"300\" is based off of which famous battle?", "answer": "The Battle of Thermopylae", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7ce67877e98cb97778a41", "question": "What is the oldest major city in the Philippines?", "answer": "Cebu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba7f", "question": "In 1995, who became the first Asian player to be named Rookie of the Year in Major League Baseball?", "answer": "Hideo Nomo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf2f", "question": "What got its name from a Bridgeport pie company's name and lightweight pie tins?", "answer": "Frisbees", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb3", "question": "Which Egyptian city was founded by Alexander the Great in 331 BC?", "answer": "Alexandria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe733e8eec85e375820b228", "question": "What conflict was known as \"The War to End All Wars\"?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b117", "question": "In American history, what 20th century decade is often described as \"Roaring\"?", "answer": "1920's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f164bb2f9b80650dbe7f92d", "question": "Which Marvel Cinematic Universe character was frozen in ice for 66 years?", "answer": "Captain America", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7ec1ab24f84e0b9f9ffe3", "question": "The Atomium is a famous tourist attraction in which city?", "answer": "Brussels", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4b9", "question": "What is the only nation that borders both Burma and Malaysia?", "answer": "Thailand", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133942e", "question": "What is the name of the school in the 1989 movie \"Dead Poets Society\"?", "answer": "The Welton Academy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab14", "question": "In which country is the wine making area of Stellenbosch?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a262", "question": "What is the name of the summer camp in the \"Friday the 13th\" movie series?", "answer": "Camp Crystal Lake\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c03e", "question": "What is the fear of social situations called?", "answer": "Sociophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389b5", "question": "What Shakespeare play if \"All the world's a stage\"?", "answer": "As You Like It", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b7ffb533a3a814d89068c64", "question": "Whose autobiography is titled \"Long Walk to Freedom\"?", "answer": "Nelson Mandela's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339724", "question": "What is Elton John's real name?", "answer": "Reginald Dwight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe12f17e39efa6330e0fed6", "question": "Where is Great Sand Dunes National Park?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b08d01dd7bf43be5e78e", "question": "What company created the first mass-produced portable computer?", "answer": "Osborne Computers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa5ad73838c5c8a417f29", "question": "What do speleologists study?", "answer": "Wild cave systems", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab94f486faa38a764be511", "question": "In the automotive world, what does the abbreviation DOHC mean?", "answer": "Dual OverHead Cam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe1f202145fb29466707395", "question": "What is the Christian holy day falling on the Thursday before Easter?", "answer": "Maundy Thursday or Holy Thursday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afd2", "question": "What US city was destroyed by an earthquake in 1906?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c523877e98cb977789ab", "question": "Which island was once named the \"Island of the Pelicans\"?", "answer": "Alcatraz Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefa5886ce05a3942286ec2", "question": "What classic music was used in the television series \"The Lone Ranger\"?", "answer": "March of the Swiss Soldiers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5901dcfd709c1c34536e6eb7", "question": "On Saturday Night Live, who played the recurring character known as \"Samurai Futaba\"?", "answer": "John Belushi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2be", "question": "Who played the role of Liz Lemon on the TV show \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "Tina Fey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a466", "question": "In what state would you find the Black Rock Desert?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c75a", "question": "What is another name for the disease known as Varicella?", "answer": "Chickenpox", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba3a", "question": "Thomas Jefferson is depicted on what US coin?", "answer": "5 cent coin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe0e316fcbed638185eaa20", "question": "What is the most widely-spoken language in South America?", "answer": "Portuguese", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a009", "question": "What color are Chip 'n' Dale's noses?", "answer": "Black and red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a76", "question": "On \"Sesame Street\", which two characters live in an apartment at 123 Sesame Street?", "answer": "Bert and Ernie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff3c3094f032c0db195b489", "question": "Who was the first European to discover New Zealand?", "answer": "Abel Janszoon Tasman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cacc", "question": "Which bone is known as the Patella?", "answer": "The kneecap", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ae1", "question": "Hamlet was the Prince of which country?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6ee", "question": "What does \"green lumber\" mean to carpenters?", "answer": "Lumber that is not yet dry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c73b877e98cb977789c9", "question": "Which national capital does the Vltava River flow through?", "answer": "Prague", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b581", "question": "What year was the first iPad released?", "answer": "2010", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ae9444574a5ce6b56b8247", "question": "What was Agatha Christie's second husband's profession?", "answer": "Archaeologist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef32ed6ce05a3942286e00", "question": "How many U.S. states are needed to ratify an amendment for it to become part of the constitution?", "answer": "Three-fourths", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b813", "question": "What is the Jewish New Year called?", "answer": "Rosh Hashanah", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b143", "question": "Who was the first US President to be impeached by the US House of Representatives?", "answer": "Andrew Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea31ccff048f679a45aae5", "question": "How many eggs does a queen bee lay per day?", "answer": "2000", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc8", "question": "Which country gave us the dish Cullen Skink?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c4e", "question": "Who is the Roman goddess of love?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a9e95be7ccba3ffe45786e3", "question": "What do you add to Advocaat to make a Snowball\u00a0cocktail?", "answer": "Lemonade", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4de3306d333868d34d710", "question": "What name is given to Britain\u2019s policy of avoiding strict enforcement of parliamentary laws on early American colonies?", "answer": "Salutary neglect", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ab", "question": "Who does Emma Watson play in the Harry Potter films?", "answer": "Hermione", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c5f3fbde8045e48466b3", "question": "A \"bloat\" refers to a group of what animal?", "answer": "Hippopotamus -- A group of hippos consist of 10 to 20 females, their young, and one male hippo.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393b6", "question": "Who does Jabba intend to feed to Sarlacc in the movie \"Star Wars - Return of the Jedi\"?", "answer": "Luke and Han", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b671", "question": "Someone who is called a \"flash in the pan\" could also be described as what?", "answer": "A one-hit wonder", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990f4effa5fdd6dd25324e9", "question": "What country borders Central African Republic to the east?", "answer": "South Sudan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adb7", "question": "Portia Simpson-Miller was the leader of what country?", "answer": "Jamaica", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ea", "question": "Who is the developer of the game series \"Gran Turismo\"?", "answer": "Polyphony Digital", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e1d", "question": "Besides \"Hey Jude\", what other Beatles song title begins with the word \"Hey\"?", "answer": "Hey Bulldog", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bffb", "question": "What is the hobby of a \"twitcher\"?", "answer": "Bird watching", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a899dc260d398dc9cf7a6ae", "question": "Which year did Henry Kissinger receive the Nobel Peace Prize?", "answer": "1973", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60121a0263c99d48cd169aff", "question": "What kind of nut is used to make marzipan?", "answer": "Almond", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390e7", "question": "What year did writer Arthur C. Clarke die?", "answer": "2008", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ae866037f28483af1e7fdd2", "question": "What is the name of the band whose songs \"All Star\" and \"I\u2019m a Believer\" were featured in the 2001 film \"Shrek\"?", "answer": "Smash Mouth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e804ffde59ea584496fea8", "question": "Archie Moore is typically associated with which sport?", "answer": "Boxing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0d7", "question": "What was Princess Diana's maiden name?", "answer": "Spencer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339149", "question": "Who wrote the \"Shogun\" series of novels?", "answer": "James Clavell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d4", "question": "Who ordered the disastrous \"Great Leap Forward\" in 1958?", "answer": "Mao Tse-tung", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a33b", "question": "Which 1980's song includes the lyric \"Creatures crawl in search of blood. To terrorize y'alls neighborhood!\"?", "answer": "Thriller", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ba8", "question": "What 1975 Oscar-winning film features the sadistic Nurse Ratched?", "answer": "One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cc2", "question": "What TV judge wrote the book \"Don't Pee on My Leg and Tell Me It's Raining\"?", "answer": "Judge Judy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339889", "question": "What 1987 Michael Caine film has a zero rating on the website Rotten Tomatoes?", "answer": "Jaws 4 - The Revenge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ec2", "question": "In what Irish city did Frank McCourt set his memoir \"Angela's Ashes\"?", "answer": "Limerick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339424", "question": "Which James Bond actor also appeared in the movie \"Lara Croft: Tomb Raider\"?", "answer": "Daniel Craig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59029f62cad1ec93f27df75f", "question": "What is the thin layer of foam on top of an espresso called?", "answer": "Crema", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a6", "question": "What continent includes Iran?", "answer": "Asia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac02", "question": "The Plains of Abraham are located in which country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea3bc5ff048f679a45ab37", "question": "What kind of plant stem is soft and green?", "answer": "Herbaceous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9f356ff048f679a45aabf", "question": "What are the lakes of Titan made of?", "answer": "Methane", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133994e", "question": "Who played the title role in the 2005 film \"Capote\"?", "answer": "Philip Seymour Hoffman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be29", "question": "What January 6, 1994, act got Shane Shant a four-year prison sentence?", "answer": "Kneecapping Nancy Kerrigan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ae866977f28483af1e7fdd4", "question": "What is the name of the musician best known for his 1993 song \"What is Love\"?", "answer": "Haddaway", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bef9", "question": "What was the first magazine to publish a hologram on its cover?", "answer": "National Geographic", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ed", "question": "What was Daniel's last name in 1984 film \"The Karate Kid\"?", "answer": "LaRusso", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397d8", "question": "Which cartoon character had the vital statistics of 19-19-19?", "answer": "Olive Oyl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65723ae7e414034b5aed7", "question": "Where were the Declaration of Independence, the Constitution, and the Bill of Rights stored during World War II?", "answer": "Fort Knox", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa7f", "question": "What is Krung Thep is more commonly known as?", "answer": "Bangkok", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb5ce75dad637d903c8820", "question": "What country is nicknamed \"the land of a thousand lakes\"?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f93", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"Sayonara\"?", "answer": "Miyoshi Umeki", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a11f", "question": "Who won an Academy Award in 1970 for directing the film \"Midnight Cowboy\"?", "answer": "John Schlesinger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d118f64fea7fe947a2228a", "question": "An adventurous penguin Tennessee Tuxedo had a sidekick named what?", "answer": "Chumley", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ca3bec44f0f6af5b066629", "question": "What Canadian professional snooker player is nicknamed \"The Grinder\"?", "answer": "Cliff Thorburn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff3cf1b4f032c0db195b48f", "question": "Who was the first Catholic pope?", "answer": "The Roman Catholic Church sees\u00a0Peter\u00a0as the first pope", "category": "history"}, {"id": "593c4a6eb8198b9a2b07795d", "question": "Who played the male lead role in the film \"Clash of the Titans\"?", "answer": "Sam Worthington", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbc1", "question": "For what college did Dan Marino play football?", "answer": "University of Pittsburgh", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aed5", "question": "In what year was Billy the Kid born?", "answer": "1859", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339771", "question": "Which actor plays Tony Montana in Scarface?", "answer": "Al Pacino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a91", "question": "Where did the Yellow Brick Road lead to?", "answer": "Emerald City", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b48d", "question": "Which country were the 2016 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8fe", "question": "How far is the free throw line from the backboard in basketball?", "answer": "15 feet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5fff6ce05a3942286e49", "question": "Who was the first horse to win the Triple Crown?", "answer": "Sir Barton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0f5", "question": "In 1976-1977 season in 80 games, the Montreal Canadiens set the NHL record for how many points in a season?", "answer": "132", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be18", "question": "Which modern instrument was called the sackbut until the nineteenth century?", "answer": "The trombone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d7f", "question": "Who was the real-life model for the character of Abe Ravelstein in the novel \"Ravelstein\"?", "answer": "Allan Bloom", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f9f3dc7af848b908361b868", "question": "Why was Hitler's response in D-Day so delayed?", "answer": "He was asleep and his subordinates were under orders to not wake him up", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0fb", "question": "Who was the first Canadian-born boxer to win the heavyweight championship?", "answer": "Tommy Burns", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff50faad24dd593ee3eacc5", "question": "Which US state has the highest relative humidity?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae85", "question": "In 1800, John Adams became the first US president to live where?", "answer": "In the White House", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8d8", "question": "What is the maximum number of lines of symmetry a rectangle can have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba63", "question": "How many scoops of raisins go into each box of Kellogg's Raisin Bran?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8bf", "question": "What plant is traditionally worn on St. Patrick's Day?", "answer": "Shamrock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ca", "question": "What bird, also known as a Man O'War, can glide for hours without flapping its wings?", "answer": "Magnificent Frigatebird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a6c", "question": "What was the name of the 80\u2019s band formed by Roland Orzabal and Curt Smith?", "answer": "Tears for Fears", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a141", "question": "Rod Stewart's second album was called after which alley?", "answer": "Gasoline Alley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395eb", "question": "In The Simpsons, what kind of footwear does Grampa usually sport?", "answer": "Slippers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f27", "question": "\"The Great Rock 'n' Roll Swindle\" is a mockumentary about what band?", "answer": "The Sex Pistols", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69aab20565ad31a57c756", "question": "In the Bible, who is the wife of Boaz?", "answer": "Ruth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e1d6fe83fe1f2a824b99", "question": "What was the \"The Blitz\"?", "answer": "A term used for Germany\u2019s bombing campaign on London", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febd6f97e83c707845b2170", "question": "When was the first year the three-point shot was introduced to the NBA?", "answer": "1979", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa388bc73aa70ea0b70ad2", "question": "What is the state motto for the U.S. state Texas?", "answer": "\"Friendship\"", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b11a", "question": "Along with Karl Marx, who wrote \"The Communist Manifesto\" in 1848?", "answer": "Frederich Engels", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b241", "question": "What royal subject married Timothy Laurence?", "answer": "Princess Anne", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909d1a4bb53d1af65886503", "question": "Who wrote the 1958 book \"Journey to Christmas\"?", "answer": "B. J. Chute", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b23aed38f1a2238a7cb2b3d", "question": "What two countries noticed that they had the same flag at the 1936 Olympics in Berlin?", "answer": "Haiti and Liechtenstein", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eef", "question": "According to its first line, in what city is the Band's song \"The Weight\" set?", "answer": "Nazareth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c5", "question": "Is it true that there is more vitamin C in a sweet red pepper than in a Valencia orange?", "answer": "Yes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fe0", "question": "What are the hotel-inspired names of the two old men who heckle \"The Muppet Show\"?", "answer": "Statler and Waldorf", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133952c", "question": "What John Wayne film, set during the Civil War, was based on a true story?", "answer": "The Horse Soldiers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c89d5b011619dd6d415485", "question": "In what season of South Park did the boys claim that Butters wrote the book \"Scrotie McBoogerballs\"?", "answer": "Season 14", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c82a", "question": "What substance makes feces brown and jaundice sufferers yellow?", "answer": "Bilirubin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b5", "question": "Which movie star published an autobiography in 2002 entitled \"Lucky Man\"?", "answer": "Michael J. Fox", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cdc02e347d002c297e4e4", "question": "What is the capital of Belgium?", "answer": "Brussels", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339789", "question": "What two characters from \"The Little Rascals\" are named after plants?", "answer": "Alfalfa and Buckwheat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2ca", "question": "What is the minimum number of bars on an abacus?", "answer": "Nine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f43", "question": "Who created the character of Fozzie Bear?", "answer": "Jim Henson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339214", "question": "What is the name of the soap opera that Miranda loves watching in \"Sex and the City\"?", "answer": "Jules and Mimi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2d1", "question": "What is the abbreviation for trinitrotoluene?", "answer": "TNT", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5af250b5b63e5727cf5a4837", "question": "Which famous French civil engineer is rumoured to have designed Angola\u2019s Iron Palace?", "answer": "Gustave Eiffel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ae3", "question": "Which French artist, born in 1834 was best known for his paintings of ballet dancers?", "answer": "Edgar Degas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a23b", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Madman Across the Water\"?", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b103", "question": "What infamous gangster was betrayed by \"the lady in red\"?", "answer": "John Dillinger", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe76b30eec85e375820b2bd", "question": "Where did Oktoberfest originate?", "answer": "Munich, Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a57220565ad31a57c7cc", "question": "In which ancient culture were turkeys believed to be gods?", "answer": "Maya", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ac9", "question": "Who portrays Tom Clancy's hero Jack Ryan in the movie \"The Sum of All Fears\"?", "answer": "Ben Affleck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8a96901dd7bf43be5e74d", "question": "What is celebrated on the 2nd Saturday in June in the United Kingdom?", "answer": "The queen's birthday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4a1", "question": "Which mountain is the highest in Australia?", "answer": "Mount Kosciuszko", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be6c", "question": "What is Ohio Stadium also known as?", "answer": "The Horseshoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af30", "question": "From what terrible disease did Robert the Bruce suffer?", "answer": "Leprosy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b448", "question": "What year was Joseph Merrick, also known as Elephant Man, born?", "answer": "1862", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab89", "question": "Phnom Penh is the capital of which Asian country?", "answer": "Cambodia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba1a", "question": "What figure did the tobacco company R.J. Reynolds decommission in 1997?", "answer": "Joe Camel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad2d", "question": "The Supreme Court decision that legalized abortion in the US was referred to by what case name?", "answer": "Roe vs. Wade", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffb68cb5dad637d903c8844", "question": "The unofficial Wei\u00dfwurst\u00e4quator, or \"white sausage equator\", separates Bavaria and the south from the rest of which country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2c8", "question": "Over its 7 season run, how many episodes of the TV show \"30 Rock\" were aired?", "answer": "138", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7e02ff048f679a45ac05", "question": "Astraphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Lightening or thunder", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe901ee01dd7bf43be5e867", "question": "What is the world's largest aircraft by wingspan?", "answer": "Antonov An-225 Mriya", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c7", "question": "What is the name of Warren Beaty's famous sister?", "answer": "Shirley MacLaine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3ee", "question": "What is the Northern Tropic also called?", "answer": "Tropic of Cancer", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e63afe83fe1f2a824bc9", "question": "Who ultimately succeeded King Alfred the Great as \"King of the Anglo-Saxons\"?", "answer": "Edward the Elder", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a7", "question": "How many different falling pieces are there in the game Tetris?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c642877e98cb977789b5", "question": "Bibimbap is a traditional rice dish from which region?", "answer": "Korea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5cefc089948005ec986edcdc", "question": "Who is the third member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Haseul", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede5216ce05a3942286de7", "question": "What is television chef Rachael Ray's signature phrase?", "answer": "Yum-O", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ed", "question": "What was the name of Dan Ackroyd\u2019s butler in the movie \"Trading Places\"?", "answer": "Coleman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4eac106d333868d34d75c", "question": "What was the first Nazi concentration camp?", "answer": "Dachau (Nohra opened in March 1933 as a re-education center. Dachau opened after and became a model for future death camps and is considered to be the first)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c27c", "question": "What is the study of fossils called?", "answer": "Paleontology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab06", "question": "What was Genghis Khan's birth name?", "answer": "Temujin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8b6", "question": "In what city would you find Balboa Park?", "answer": "San Diego", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be9d", "question": "What bathroom cleaner was originally advertised by the Scrubbing Bubbles?", "answer": "Dow bathroom cleaner", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c3e976febfabb9c85d8a964", "question": "Which part of the human eye controls the size of the pupil?", "answer": "The Iris", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5da", "question": "In which city does the White Nile meet the Blue Nile?", "answer": "Khartoum", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefa49c6ce05a3942286eb5", "question": "The Stay Puff Marshmallow Man originally appeared in which film?", "answer": "Ghostbusters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c283", "question": "How often are brain cells replaced?", "answer": "Never", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7bd0c877e98cb97778952", "question": "What river runs through Baghdad?", "answer": "Tigris", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "590722383745b36be73039fd", "question": "What international company is said to have influenced the image of the modern-day Santa Claus?", "answer": "Coca-Cola", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fb0882bcf631c2414a13b5a", "question": "What does \"Valar Morghulis\" mean in High Valyrian?", "answer": "All men must die", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133befc", "question": "Which African country has a domain of .tn?", "answer": "Tunisia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ee", "question": "What organization in the Harry Potter series is named after Dumbledore's patronus?", "answer": "Order of the Phoenix", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b785", "question": "The person who invented machine-spun cotton candy was what kind of a doctor?", "answer": "A dentist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b80b", "question": "What holiday comes right before All Saints' Day?", "answer": "Halloween", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4e39306d333868d34d72d", "question": "Which city served as the capital of the Ottoman Empire?", "answer": "Constantinople", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c78b", "question": "How many oxygen atoms does a molecule of ozone have?", "answer": "3", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e21", "question": "What movie is loosely based on Philip K. Dick's novel \"Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep\"?", "answer": "Blade Runner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3e5", "question": "What is the capital of Monaco?", "answer": "Monaco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e02", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek goddess Eris?", "answer": "Discordia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c77e", "question": "What is the hardest known naturally occurring mineral?", "answer": "Diamond", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133954a", "question": "Who starred as Buffy in the TV show \"Buffy the Vampire Slayer\"?", "answer": "Sarah Michelle Gellar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec24c58dc25ca9e12ef63a", "question": "What was the very first Andrew Lloyd Webber musical to be adapted to film?", "answer": "Jesus Christ Superstar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4afd49076251badbeabf", "question": "What was the first food to be intentionally microwaved?", "answer": "Popcorn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c77d45024f0f7a362efd555", "question": "What song has the lyrics \"I don't ever wanna feel, like I did that day\"?", "answer": "Under the Bridge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aff2", "question": "During what century did the telegraph link both North American coasts?", "answer": "19th century", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe69a4320565ad31a57c751", "question": "What Russian figure was assassinated by Ramon Mercader in 1940?", "answer": "Leon Trotsky", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6008d9c9f4f3bc4a292f8612", "question": "What was the British royal family known as before becoming the House of Windsor?", "answer": "Up until 1917, the Royals were known as the Saxe-Coburgs (and sometimes as the Saxe-Coburg-Gothas).", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff7bcbc2b316f4693fb678c", "question": "A kirby-grip is the British name for what hair accessory?", "answer": "Bobby pin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca5a", "question": "Like the majority of reptiles and fish, monotremes are mammals that do what?", "answer": "Lay eggs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59cdb6a365ff7d326b622a98", "question": "Who did Perseus turn into stone with Medusa's head?", "answer": "Atlas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600cbffa6de0eb824d4052d6", "question": "Where is the world's largest greenhouse?", "answer": "Cornwall, England -- The Eden Project is home to more than one million plants. It features two hexagonally-patterned biomes.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6018bcb0d96d05b23b28165a", "question": "Who was murdered along with OJ Simpson\u2019s estranged wife Nicole?", "answer": "Ronald Goldman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339868", "question": "In Disney's \"Dumbo\", what kind of animal is Dumbos only friend?", "answer": "A Mouse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad31", "question": "Elizabeth Bowes-Lyon was better known by what name?", "answer": "The Queen Mother", "category": "history"}, {"id": "591c37dc815febcc896f9275", "question": "What is the fourth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Cancer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febb5c17e83c707845b2121", "question": "What dictates whether a sea turtle is male or female?", "answer": "Incubation temperature", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb9d", "question": "What national news magazine published its first issue in February 1933, as a competitor of \"Time\"?", "answer": "Newsweek", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133975a", "question": "Whose music is featured in the musical movie Mamma Mia!?", "answer": "ABBA", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590722c63745b36be7303a02", "question": "What year did Mariah Carey release the song \"All I Want for Christmas Is You\"?", "answer": "1994", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5aab2fc158d116dab4aecb4d", "question": "In the opera, \"The Marriage of Figaro\", who did Figaro marry?", "answer": "Sussana", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133919e", "question": "Who played Renton in the 1996 movie \"Trainspotting\"?", "answer": "Ewan McGregor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59675c4d2b59efe0e9417e94", "question": "What was Vince Gill\u2019s last #1 as a solo recording artist?", "answer": "Tryin\u2019 To Get over You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2de", "question": "What year did actor Stan Laurel die?", "answer": "1965", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76f4ceec85e375820b2e6", "question": "What is the northernmost place in the contiguous United States?", "answer": "Northwest Angle, Minnesota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c70d", "question": "What \"-itis\" is an inflammation of the liver?", "answer": "Hepatitis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2d7a02596a59cbdfbd3b8", "question": "Martha Jane Canary was a sharpshooting frontierswoman better known as?", "answer": "Calamity Jane", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a72f", "question": "The Simi Valley is located in which US state?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c0e", "question": "How were composer George Gershwin and lyricist Ira Gershwin related?", "answer": "They were brothers", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339849", "question": "Who was the protagonist in Disney's \"The Little Mermaid\"?", "answer": "Ariel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f6b4ff048f679a45aadd", "question": "What did Albert Einstein win the Nobel Prize for in 1921?", "answer": "For his discovery of the law of the photoelectric effect", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c228", "question": "What ingredients go into making Orgeat syrup?", "answer": "Almonds, sugar, rose water or orange flower water", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd33", "question": "What are the small indentations on a golf ball called?", "answer": "Dimples", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339900", "question": "What was Clair Huxtable's profession on \"The Cosby Show\"?", "answer": "Lawyer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be34", "question": "How many players are there in a standard volleyball team?", "answer": "Six", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c55b", "question": "How many carbon atoms are there in an aspirin molecule?", "answer": "9", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3ad", "question": "How many wings does a butterfly have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5cd40be1685cf15b733e988c", "question": "Which cartoon family lives in 742 Evergreen Terrace, Springfield, USA?", "answer": "The Simpsons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398a9", "question": "What musical tells the story of a group of young artists struggling to survive in New York?", "answer": "Rent", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd2", "question": "What TV show did \"The Facts of Life\" spin off from?", "answer": "Diff'rent Strokes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008c40cf842fa4c4ba969e", "question": "With which horror film series would you associate the character Leatherface?", "answer": "Texas Chainsaw Massacre", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae9457574a5ce6b56b8248", "question": "Barbara, Carignan, Cinsaut, and Nebbilo are verities of what?", "answer": "Italian wine grapes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab7f", "question": "Sierra Leone has direct access to which ocean?", "answer": "Atlantic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a828", "question": "In which US city is the United States Naval Academy located?", "answer": "Annapolis, Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbc5", "question": "How long is a fortnight?", "answer": "Two weeks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcc0", "question": "Who met longtime best friend Gayle King in 1976?", "answer": "Oprah Winfrey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3e92f38e4e5d4832e630f", "question": "What was the infamous Bloody Mary's occupation?", "answer": "Queen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe1f210145fb29466707396", "question": "What is the Christian holy day falling on the Thursday before Easter?", "answer": "Maundy Thursday or Holy Thursday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5902a012cad1ec93f27df767", "question": "What are the four primary ingredients of a traditional Irish coffee?", "answer": "Irish whisky, coffee, sugar and cream", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8cc5494b094db9158309e", "question": "What was the name of the protagonist in the 2016 film \u201cZootopia\u201d?", "answer": "Judy Hopps", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b478", "question": "The Battle of the Plains of Abraham was fought outside which city?", "answer": "Quebec City", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac82", "question": "Who founded the city of Philadelphia?", "answer": "William Penn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015ddc9fe83fe1f2a824b63", "question": "What color was considered appropriate for baby boys in the 17th century?", "answer": "Pink", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffe502447818f5674af01b8", "question": "\"Les Fauves\" was a name given to a group of artists that also included Matisse. What is its literal meaning of \"Les Fauves\"?", "answer": "The Wild Beasts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c042", "question": "What name was given to textile workers who opposed modernisation during the 19th century?\u00a0", "answer": "Luddites\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f169b5f7c52aae91cc07d3", "question": "Who played \"Hawkeye\" in the 1970 film \"MASH\"?", "answer": "Donald Sutherland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5e2", "question": "Which US state is closest to Cuba?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396eb", "question": "On the Academy Awards statue, what is Oscar standing on?", "answer": "A reel of film", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b5a", "question": "What was the first ever animated film to be nominated for the Best Picture Oscar?", "answer": "Beauty and the Beast", "category": "entertainment"}]